Daniel Mateo Neira

Email: mateo.neira.16@ucl.ac.uk Web: https://mateoneira.github.io/

Phone: +44 739 732 5982

Address: 8C Cornwall Road, N4 4PH, London, UK.

INTERESTS

Mateo is a second year PhD student at UCL through the Alan Turing Institute Doctoral Programme. He is interested in modelling, understanding, and predicting innovation, economic growth, and social resilience in urban systems. His research seeks to deepen the quantitative understanding of human behaviour within cities and the coupling and interactions between social, economic, and spatial systems. Particularly, he aims to understand the impact of infrastructural networks on different urban process and dynamics at inter and intra urban systems through a multiplex network framework and stochastic modelling.

EDUCATION

- PhD. Urban modelling and complexity, University College London, (supervised by Dr Elsa Arcaute) 2018-Present
- MSc. Smart Cities and Urban Analytics, University College London, 2017 (Distinction)
- BSc. Architecture and Urbanism, Universidad de Cuenca, 2015

PUBLICATIONS

- Law, Stephen, and Mateo Neira. ""An unsupervised approach to geographical knowledge discovery using street level and street network images."" Proceedings of the 3rd ACM SIGSPATIAL International Workshop on AI for Geographic Knowledge Discovery. 2019.
- Hermida, M.A. Neira, M. Cabrera-Jara, N. Osorio, P. "Resilience in Latin American cities: behaviour vs. space quality in the riverbanks of the Tomebamba River." *Procedia Engineering*. Vol 198, p.467-481. https://doi.org/10.12972/susb.20170012
- Osorio, P. Neira, M. Hermida, M.A. "Historic relationship between urban dwellers and the Tomebamba River." nternational Journal of Sustainable Building Technology and Urban Development, Vol. 8. No. 2, 144-152/
- Orellana, D. Neira, M. Guerrero, M.L. Samaniego P. Hermida, M.A. "New geotools for urban studies." *Proceedings of SBE16 Sustainable Urban Communities towards a Nearly Zero Impact Built Environment*, Victória, Brasil. Vol 2. P.857-866. ISBN 978-85-92631-00-0.

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

2018-Pr Doctoral Researcher Alan Turing Institute

2015–16 Research Assistant

llacta Lab - Sustainable Cities Research Group, Universidad de Cuenca Principal Investigator: Daniel Orellana and Maria Augusta Hermida

2011–13 Research Assistant

Faculty of Architecture and Urbanism, Universidad de Cuenca Principal Investigator: Boris Orellana

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

2017 Teaching Assistant

Tutorial: Road networks and scaling laws Oxford Summer School in Economic Networks

2011 Teaching Assistant (Spring 2011, Summer 2011)

Mathematics II

Architecture, University of Cuenca, Ecuador.

HONOURS AND AWARDS

2018 PhD Full Scholarship by the Alan Turing Doctoral Programme.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

2017-Pr Foster + Partners

Urban Designer & Spatial Data Scientist

London, United Kingdom

2017 Signalbox

Spatial Data Researcher - Tech Lead

London, United Kingdom

2014–15 Duran Hermida Arquitectos Asociados

Architectural Assistant

Cuenca, Ecuador

OTHER ACTIVITIES

Voluntary Organizations and Projects

2014-16 Colectivo Cuenca Ciudad para Vivir Active Member Cuenca, Ecuador 2016 Cuenca Conversa Co-Founder / Co-Organizer Cuenca, Ecuador

SKILLS AND METHODS

Statistical and Computational Methods

Multivariate statistics and machine learning, data mining and wrangling, network science, Python (including numpy, scipy, pandas, matplotlib, statsmodels, networkx, and scikit-learn, PyTorch, TensorFlow), web scraping, R, JavaScript, SQL.

Geospatial Methods

GIS, spatial analysis, network analysis, QGIS, ArcGIS, PostGIS, geopandas, Spatial Interaction Models.

Data Visualization and Design

JavaScript (including D3), OpenFrameworks, Processing, Tableau.

Updated August 2020